This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
それは どこにでもある日常
家族の 朝の風景
It was a normal family's typical morning scene.
また やっちゃった
Ah, I've done it again!
それじゃ こなちゃん 行ってくるわね
うん いってらっしゃい ママ
Alright, Kona. I'm off!
だけど ママはそのまま二度と戻ってこなかった
Yeah. Have a nice day, Mom.
But after that, my mom never came home again.
寒い
このまま私を凍らせて 永遠に保存してくれたらいいのに
It's so cold...
If only that coldness could envelope and freeze me forever...
これは ひどい
何という 厨二病ポエム
Duhuhu.
How awful.
Was that some kind of pretentious poem?
残酷なる時は いつか
In the end, time unforgiving
契約の地さえ引き裂くの
たくさんが生み出す恐怖
Will draw the blood of covenant
Everything scatters, leaving void
真理のために今ここにいるよ
意外なCrazy
But we're here for the greater good
We Meet
目眩くこのシーン うかつな選択
Crazier than everyone, we need to dazzle
The stage with our careless justice
浮かび行く景色はやがて鮮やかに
And the scenery floating by becomes clearer
時間をすり抜ける
咆筺のメシア
As the Messiah of the Shoutbox slips through time
笑って 泣いて
僕らの一つの夢
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
願って 叫んで
どこまでも遠くへ
Laugh and cry for our one and only dream
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
走って 飛ばして
気持ちの集まる場所
Pray, shout, and struggle right down to the end
Run and break that place where feelings gather
愛しすぎるこの空の下で
Under this sky, oh so dear
明日を証明したくて
We're fighting for the future
What a mad world
A cold wind blew through with November.
１１月に入って風も ずいぶんと冷たくなった
ロボ２号機の組み立ては まあ 順調に進んでる
The construction of the second robot progressed quite well.
Whoa...
すごい
ＡＲの中だけですけどね
It's only AR so far though...
現実は まだ
駆動システムが まだ未定だから組み立てられないんだよね
We don't know how to move it yet, so we can't build it...
何とか モノ… を使って
I was thinking we could use... stuff to build motors.
モーターが作れないかって思ってるんだけど
皆さん 早いですね
You're so early, guys!
Since she came back from Tokyo last month,
先月 東京から戻ってきた綯さんは
Ms. Nae's been accompanying us here as the project director.
俺たちがここを使うとき 監督として同席してくれるようになった
Good morning, Ms. Nae!
おはようございます 綯さん
Good morning.
はい おはようございます
せっかくの土日なんだし たまにはどこか遊びに行ったら
It's finally the weekend.
Why aren't you somewhere partying?
Kaito, don't make fun of older women.
海翔君 あんまり 年上のお姉さんをからかっちゃ駄目だよ
Bad boys are punished by...
そんな悪い子は
こちょこちょの刑にしてあげます
extensive tickling!
こちょこちょ
ちょっと やめてよ
Stop it!
More importantly, Ms. Nae,
そんなことより綯さん 今日はプレゼントがあるんです
we've got a present for you today.
A present?
プレゼント？
Yeah!
はい せ～の
One-two!
Happy birthday to you!
誕生日おめでとう
って みんな歌ってよ
Come on, sing along!
ご… ごめんなさい え～と 照れちゃって
Sorry, I got embarrassed!
Likewise.
右に同じく
I was getting tickled to death.
俺はこちょこちょの刑のせいで歌えない
もしかしてみんな 私の誕生日を？
How come you all know my birthday? I'm so surprised!
よく知ってましたね すごいサプライズです
これ うちらからプレゼント
Here, our present for you!
Thank you so much! I'm moved!
ありがとう 感激です
Can I open it?
開けてもいいですか
Sure, go on! Kai chose it.
どうぞ どうぞ 選んだのはカイなんですよ
これって サイクリング用のサングラスですね
These are cycling sunglasses! So cute!
カワイイ
I'll be holding them dear!
大切にしますね
It really looks good on you.
すごく似合ってると思います
そういえば フラウ坊は？
What about Frau Bow by the way?
まあ 来るわけないでしょ
Did you really expect her to come?
「ツイぽ」で会話はしてるけど 俺も ここ２～３カ月会ってないし
I talk with her over Twipo, but we haven't met face-to-face for 2 or 3 months already.
the last gunvarrel ep's a mess, not even funny
dat last ep FUUUUUUK
Is it true that the director killed the whole staff and went missing?
Are they ever gonna find her?
srsly a 12-year-old could write a better script...
hella troll ending for 150 episodes lol
Is it true that the director killed the whole staff and went missing?
Are they ever gonna find her?
srsly a 12-year-old could write a better script...
hella troll ending for 150 episodes lol
Don't you dare talk bad about Gunvarrel!
What's that? What's that?
何 何 それ
What do you think it is?
何だと思う
A parabola antenna?
パラボラアンテナですか
お前の目は節穴か
Are you blind or what?
俺の自作のバーニアだ
It's my own vernier.
こいつを２号機に…
You could use it on No. 2...
We couldn't! It doesn't fly! It doesn't even jump!
取り付けないよ
だって ガンつく２は飛ばないし ジャンプもしないし
It doesn't need to. You could use the vernier for exhaustion.
飛ばなくてもいいから バーニアで燃料噴射させようじゃねえか
You'd put on 10 verniers in total.
ちなみに 搭載するバーニアは全部で１０基な
Oh! Six on the back?
背中に ６基
違えだろ ４基だ
Nope. Four.
ついでに ホバー機能を付けて
It could hover as well.
"I'll be your stepping stone!" is it? Then we should paint it black and purple!
「俺を踏み台にした！」って？
じゃあ ペイントは黒と紫で
What exactly are you two talking about?
２人とも何の話をしてるんですか
黒い三連星
The Black Tristar!
That's nonsense.
ナンセンスですね
You're right! It's nonsense!
そう ナンセンス
Get it, Doc? We can't put on verniers!
ドク バーニアなんて搭載しないからね
Geez, you kids are boring.
んだよ つまんねえがきどもだな
You're overdoing it, Doc. You just got out of hospital.
ドクってば 元気になり過ぎ 退院したばっかりなのに
So what do you want anyway?
で 今日は何の用だ
そう 実は ドクにお願いがあって
Ah right, I've got a request for you...
What's this?
こりゃ 何だ
A monopole.
モノポール
Could we build motors for the No. 2 with this?
これを使って
２号機のモーター作れないかな
おもしれえじゃねえか
Now this looks interesting.
やっぱり 何度読んでも理解できない
This makes no sense no matter how many times I read it.
"Subliminal."
サブリミナル
プロジェクト・アトゥム ロボットの反乱
"Project Atom."
"Robot rebellion."
何 それ
What?
I tried summing it up in three points.
３行で まとめてみました
That didn't make it easier to understand.
まとめても分かんないよ
A robot rebellion is totally unrealistic.
ロボットの反乱なんて 現実味なさ過ぎだし
Ah, I knew you'd be here!
やっぱり ここにいた
Aki!
アキちゃん
Whatcha reading?
何 見てたの
Nothing.
何でもない
じゃあ ドクは引き受けてくれたんだ
So Doc accepted the job?
Yeah.
He said he's gonna look up stuff first,
まずは 色々調べてみるって
後は モーターを制御するプログラムだけ
then it'll only take a program to control the motor.
カイ フラウ坊の説得 よろしくね
Good luck convincing Frau Bow!
俺を動かしたいなら まず 『キルバラ』勝負でしょ
You know you'll need to win in Kill Ballad first if you want me to do something.
そう言うと思った
I thought you'd say that.
綯さんって 今 『キルバラ』のランキング
Ms. Nae rose to rank 200 really fast!
We've got 4 months to go until the Expo!
２００位くらいまで急上昇してるんだって
万博まで あと４カ月
Let's show the world we can build the GunPro-2!
ガンつく２ 絶対 完成させてみせる
But first we'll have to pass the preliminary examinations next month.
その前に 来月の予備審査が控えてます
Are we going to make it in time?
間に合うんですか
Don't worry. I'll make the greatest entry sheet ever.
エントリーシートは うちの方で完璧なのを作るから
The topic is "Bring world peace by love and justice!"
ちなみにテーマは 愛と正義で全人類に平和を
What do you think? It's like a robot anime, isn't it?
どう どう 何かロボットアニメみたいでしょ
It's nonsense.
ナンセンスですね
Yay!
やった
Thought she wouldn't respond.
やっぱ 出ないか
Yashio...
八汐… 先輩
You sound sick. Are you okay?
調子悪そうだね 大丈夫？
I'm... hungry.
おなか すいた
差し入れ持ってきたよ
Brought you some food.
Kagoshima special potato flavored Pocchi.
鹿児島限定 安納芋味のポッチィ
I d-don't have time for food!
め… 飯 食ってる場合じゃねえ
そんなことより 八汐先輩
More importantly, Yashio, can I...
ちょ… ちょっと お願いが
Can I...
お… お願い おｋ？
何だよ
What?
ちょ… ちょっと 先輩の指先をぺろぺろさせてほしいんです
Can I lick your finger?
Lick-lick!
ぺろぺろ
Kona, you're really a freak.
こなちゃんは ホントに変態だな
D-Don't get me wrong!
ち… ち… 違うし
It's a human instinct, a part of our elemental identity!
これは人間の本能っつーか 根源的なアイデンティティーっつーか
Even babies suck on their own thumb.
赤ちゃんだって 自分の親指しゃぶってるでしょ
But why?!
それは なぜだ
Cause they're kids.
坊やだからさ
Duhuhu. lol shot down my own argument.
セルフツッコミ 乙
You seem quite hyped. What's up?
ずいぶんテンション高いみたいだけど どうかしたの
Found out something about the cheaters?
チーターの件とか その後何か進展はあった？
ぞ… 続報はなし
Nothing new.
警察も真面目に取り合ってくれないって チューチューやすまさが言ってた
That fart Yasumasa said the police wouldn't look into it either.
ただ
Just...
Just what?
ただ？
It's about that 4th Kimijima Report you found.
こ… この前 先輩が見つけた君島レポート ナンバー４の件
You figured out something?
何か分かったの
The leaked last episode of Gunvarrel had a very similar message to it. Duhuhu.
りゅ… 流出した『ガンヴァレル』の最終話から
あれと よく似たメッセージが出てきたんだお
What do you mean?
どういう意味
サブリミナル パスワード 黒歴史
Subliminal. Password. Dark history.
No need to sum it up in three points. Elaborate.
３行にまとめなくていいよ もっと長くて
S-So you want to chat more with me?
つ… つまり 八汐先輩は 私ともっとおしゃべりしたいんですね
密室で ふ… ２人きりで
In a closed room! Alone with me!
What eroge is this?
それ 何てエロゲ
Could you at least try to focus on the topic?
いちいち 話 そらさなくていいから
T-The leaked last episode is only a 4 minute and 31 second long crudely pieced together video.
も… もともと 流出した最終話は４分３１秒しかない
ぶ… ぶつ切れ編集の映像だったわけだが
B-But there were 19 unrelated images included as well that didn't make any sense.
そこに ぜ… 全部で１９カ所意味不明の画像が差し込まれていた
その画像を ぜ… 全部ノイズ除去してレベル補正したら
D-Denoising and level correcting those images resulted in other, subliminal images.
さらに 別のサブリミナル画像が含まれていた
I-Images like this.
こ… これが問題の画像です
The location hasn't been identified yet. But look here.
場所は特定されてない
だが ここを見て
It looks like an alphabet B to me.
アルファベットの「Ｂ」に見えなくもない
Correct! Let me lick your finger!
正解 指 ぺろぺろさせろ
Freaks are requested to stay at an arm's length.
変態は近寄らないでくれるかな
サ… サ…サブリミナル映像の中に
There were similar subliminal pictures in the other 18 images as well,
隠されてた画像は 他の１８枚にもあったわけだが
それも ぜ… 全部同じ廃墟の映像っぽくて
and they all looked like they were taken in the same abandoned building.
どの画像にも 加工されたアルファベットが書き加えられていた
Every picture has an alphabet letter added to them.
Do they carry any message?
それを 全部 並べたら 意味のある文章になった？
Nope. But...
それは ない ただ
What's this?
これは
黒歴史
Dark history.
ママが女子高時代に作ったホムペ ２０年以上 放置されてた
A homepage Mom made during her high school years.
It's been abandoned for over 20 years now.
I'm surprised it's still online.
よく残ってたね
It's got the manga Mom was drawing at the time, The Maiden Poem,
当時 ママが描いたイラスト漫画 乙女ポエム
and a bulletin board for interactions.
あと 交流用の掲示板
And there's a message from your mom?
もしかして そこにお母さんの書き込んだメッセージが
October 4th, 2015.
2015年10月4日
Two weeks after Gunvarrel's last episode was cancelled.
『ガンヴァレル』最終話の放映が中止された２週間後
そのアドレスは？
What about that address?
A password?
パスワード
Yeah!
そう さっきのアルファベットはパスワードだったんだよ
Those alphabet letters were a pasword! Guess what!
な… 何だって
Gunvarrel's a tool for brainwashing!             It's propaganda!
I had to escape to prevent terror attacks all around the world
at the time of solar flares.
But they're still there.
The others are dead.
Someone stop them!
Project Atom isn't over yet.
Solar flares...
太陽嵐
Project Atom...
プロジェクト・アトゥム
Irei Store
Then what?
それで？ 弓道部のＯＢに頼んで 弓を貸してほしいって
Why would you need a bow from an old archery club member?
いったい 何をするつもりだい
Well, this and that.
まあ… ちょっとね
まっ それ 食べさえすれば詮索はしないけど
I won't delve further if you eat that,
まさか
but I very much hope you're not investigating the Kimijima reports again.
また 君島レポートのこと探ったりするんじゃないだろうね
君島レポート ナンバー５のフラグ回収状況は以下のとおりです
The release flags for Kimijima Report no. 5 are as follows.
１ 君島レポート ナンバー４を発見している
One: Find Kimijima Report No. 4.
Note by Sister Centipede: flag one is already set.
ゲジ姉より注釈 フラグ１はすでに達成済み
２ 旧種子島空港の滑走路
Two: Run from point A to point B on the old Tanegashima airport runway in 5 minutes.
ポイントＡからポイントＢまでを５分以内に走りきる
フラグ２は バイクで走って回収に成功した
I managed to release flag two by riding my bike.
Three: Complete a lap on the Nakatane Central Sports Park track field within 60 seconds.
３ 中種子中央運動公園の陸上競技トラックを６０秒で周回する
フラグ３は 自転車で走って回収
I cleared flag three by riding my bicycle.
４ 中央種子島高校 弓道場で 矢を的の中心に当てる
Four: In the old dojo of the Central Tanegashima High School, hit the bulls-eye with an arrow.
超至近距離でも 別に 問題はないよね
There were no details on the distance.
And according to your predictions,
で ゲジ姉の予想によれば
the report should be somewhere around the school?
レポートがあるのはこの学校のどこか と
はい 速やかに回収してください
Yes. Find it as soon as possible.
Then finally I found the fifth report at the school gates.
そして 俺は校門前でレポート ナンバー５を見つけた
Robotics Club
This one's as much of an enigma as the others.
相変わらず長い
半分も理解できなかったんだけど
I couldn't get half of what's written there.
ゲジ姉 短くまとめられない？
Could you sum it up, Sister Centipede? Doesn't have to be three points.
３行じゃなくていいから
太陽の活動が極大期に入ったことにより
The Earth's magnetosphere is unstable due to the Sun entering its last stage of life.
地球磁気圏も また不安定になっています
それを利用して ３００人委員会は
Using that, the Committee of 300 are trying to artificially create solar corona-like phenomenon.
太陽コロナのような現象を 人為的に引き起こそうとしているのです
つまり 人類が滅ぶってこと
So humankind would go extinct?!
Indeed, that would be the result.
そういうことになります
I should really make this thing public.
やっぱり これ 世間に公表すべきなのかな
Oh, crap.
いけねえ いけねえ
Very good! Just like that!
そうそう そんな感じ いいよ いいよ
Next try saying that one!
それじゃ 次は あれ いってみよう
Superinpei!
スーパーリンペイ
The PokeCom's acting all moody today...
どうも 今日はポケコンの調子が
Yes, it's m—
はい 私
What?! An explosion?!
爆発
Doc?!
ドク
おう どうした
Hey! What's wrong?
We heard there was an explosion...
あれ 爆発したって聞いたけど
Ah, Gou told you? He really shouldn't have.
豪のやつが話したのか 余計なこと しやがって
Grandpa, you just got out of the hospital! Don't go overboard!
おじいちゃん
病み上がりなんだから あ… あんまり無茶しないで
お… おう 心配掛けて悪かったな ジュン
Sorry for making you worry,
だがよ こいつは男のロマンってやつなんだよ
but y'know this is what makes a man's life full.
ちょっとくらい冒険しねえと モノポールほどの代物はいじれねえ
You can't get to know stuff like
monopoles unless you get adventurous.
I was prepared for the island to blow up. No regrets.
俺は 島が吹っ飛ぶ覚悟でやった 後悔はしてねえ
I'd rather if you had some.
いや そこは してください
The monopole might explode?
モノポールが爆発する可能性ってあるの
Well, for now I tried cutting it in half, and it worked out.
まあ 取りあえずぶった切ってみたんだが
大丈夫だったな
"For now"?
取りあえずって
Look!
見な
これは
What's this?
ステーキみたいだね
It looks like steak.
触っても大丈夫なんですか
Can we touch it?
It's smart. Can't burn you.
ちりっとするぐらいだな やけどするほどじゃねえ
And still it's a divine thing...
さながら 神の領域ですか
That's quite a pretentious way to put it.
何 気取った言い方してやがる
Doc,
ドク
ありのまま 話してほしい
can you tell me honestly?
Is it dangerous? Is it not?
危ないのか 危なくないのか
使えるのか 使えないのか
Can we use it? Can we not?
Those eyes of yours remind me of your sister.
その目 姉に そっくりだな
Really?
そう？
Yeah. You can't deny you're related.
やっぱり 血は争えねえな
I'm getting fired up.
たぎってきた
メール？
A mail?
Sounds like an emergency alert to me.
いや 緊急地震警報か
太陽嵐です 関東地方を直撃したと
A solar flare. It hit the Kanto area.
Emergency report
Report from the Osaka studio
The greatest solar flare in history hits Kanto area
Around 4.30 pm, a giant scale solar flare hit the Kanto region.
本日 午後４時３０分ごろ 大規模な太陽嵐が関東地方を直撃しました
アキちゃん
Aki...
カイ 東京 すごいことになってる
Kai! Tokyo's a mess...
ミサ姉とは連絡つかず
Can you get through to Misa?
No...
The greatest solar flare in history hits Kanto region
Midair above Tokyo
真っ暗です
It's all pitch black!
眠らない街と呼ばれた東京のどこにも光はありません
The city that was never said to sleep, Tokyo, is now shrouded in darkness!
The only light over there is a fire if I see right!
あそこに見える火は火事でしょうか
住宅街のようです 民家が何軒か 火事で燃えています
Dammit!
クソが
ゲンキ君 飲み物プリーズ
Genki, get me a drink plz.
Come on, a bit of thirst isn't the end of the world!
ちょっとくらい 喉が渇いたからって何だ
Genki-like lightning speed and it'll all be fine!
元気一発 気合で乗り切ろうぜ
ゲンキ君ｂｏｔはミュート状態に
Mute Genki bot.
Okay! See you again!
よし 分かった 絶対 また会おうな
The greatest solar flare in history hits Kanto region
Midair above Tokyo
Emergency report
Report from the Osaka studio
The greatest solar flare in history hits Kanto area
All metropolitan functions are still paralyzed.
首都機能は 完全にまひした状態が続いています
そんな中 制御を失ったロボットが暴走を始めたとの情報も入ってきており
There are also reports of robots having lost control running berserk.
政府は…
何という狂った世界
早急な対応を…
What a mad world...
Robot Osugi.
Was there something like that in Tokyo?
Aren't they going raid the National Diet?
Isn't that bad?
A robot rebellion...
ain't funny.
I think robots should be freed from human control now.
Kona...
こなちゃん
２０１５年 いわゆる１５年クラッシュと呼ばれたときの
The greatest solar flare in
history hits Kanto area
Solar flare
Sun
The emission of solar flares
Bow shock
Magnetopause
Magnetosphere
Plasma sheet
Radiation belt
In 2015, the so-called '15 Crash was caused by similar grand scale solar flares,
大規模太陽嵐の到達時には…
Who's it?
だ… 誰
It's Hattori Hanjuurou!
服部 半十郎さんです
Answer!
つ… つないで
Hanju, you okay?
ハ… ハンジュ 無事だったん？
Frau, you can stop this madness now!
Hattori Hanjuurou
フラウっち 今すぐ アホなまねはやめなよ
ＲＩのロボットＯＳ乗っ取るとかいたずらじゃ済まないんだから
Hacking the OS of RI robots is more than just a prank!
What are you even talking about?
おまいは何を言ってるんだ 日本語でおｋ
In Japanese please.
You're the one making robots attack people in the Tokyo blackout, aren't you?
停電中の東京でロボット暴走させて 人を襲わせてるのフラウっちでしょ
自分で『ツイぽ』でつぶやいといて 何 言ってんの
You even said it yourself on Twipo! Don't play dumb!
ツイぽ 私が？
Twipo? I did?
東京でロボットが制御不能になって 人を襲ってる事件 知ってる？
"Heard that out of control robots are
attacking people in Tokyo? I'm doing that."
それ 私がやってるのよ
I hacked the RIICH series RI's OS.
Wasn't a big deal. Sent them on a rampage.
Who leaked the last episode of Gunvarrel?
It was me of course!
If you wanna find me and get your robots back, break through my security!
This isn't me! Someone hacked my account!
これ 私じゃない
私のアカウントが 誰かに乗っ取られた
So cold!
寒っ
こなちゃん
Kona!
こなちゃん そこにいるの
Kona, are you there?
こなちゃん
Kona!
汚される
They're ruining...
They're ruining Gunvarrel...
『ガンヴァレル』が汚されちゃう
八汐先輩 助けて
Yashio... help.
それはふとした瞬間に
All those unexpected moments
君がつぶやくいくつもの言葉
As you mumble on and on
それがいつしか価値観さえも
Will overcome even my standards
超えてしまうんだよ
In the end
いくつもの別れを告げ 僕らは
All those goodbyes we said
明日への階段をのぼる
As we climb the stairway to the future
とめどなく零れ落ちる雫も
Just as raindrops fall no matter what we do
光が照らすなら この星は繋がっている
Light will always hold this planet together
奇跡のように命が集まって
Lives gather as if by some miracle
にぎやかな景色は輪郭になる
Showing the outline of a lively scene
泣きたい眩しいエピローグ
An epilogue so bright it brings tears to our eyes
取り上げる思いが
The sky painted by the hearts of those looking up
描いた空
柔らかな風が吹き
The wind blows gently stroking
Turning into a new path
新しい道となり
A path that will always
いつだってその道は
Lead us to this place
この場所に繋がってる
Tune in next week too!
Here!!
Now, Yashio!!